Rob Christopher Atalla

Kansas City Missouri, 64114 | 816.507.5957 <u>linkedin.com/in/ratalla816</u> | <u>ratalla816.github.io/professional-portfolio</u> <u>rob.atalla@gmail.com</u>

CAREER SUMMARY

Driven and tech-savvy project management professional with a relentless passion for efficiency and accuracy. Known for being teachable, personable, proactive, and facilitative, as well as a strong business acumen developed throughout a decade of logistics and P&L experience. Experienced with various development strategies, including agile, waterfall and Kaizen. Received formal training in software development and management from the University of Kansas

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROBLEM SOLVE II / IOL / ICQA / TRAINING AMBASSADOR Amazon | New Century, KS December 2021 - Present

- Troubleshoot and resolve edge case customer returns; includes updating item dispositions, repairing broken SKU's, moving inventory to proper container numbers, and using alternative methods to locate order numbers when an RMA is not available.
- Research inventory in odd locations to ensure physical and virtual quantities are maintained at equilibrium.
- Assess, modify, and design inventory control and production processes.
- Inspects processed return items for quality issues, and updates resale conditions if necessary.
- Collaborates with managers and warehouse associates across multiple departments to manage efficiency, quality, and safety.
- Coaches associates on quality defects by issuing Mastermind tickets and performing sorter and fluid load audits.
- Submit IOL and ICQA audit reports daily.

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER Western Logistics Express | North Kansas City, MO April 2021 - September 2021

- Created relationships within client organizations through cold calling, network lead prospecting, and email campaigns.
- Analyzed market data and trends to develop customer pricing strategies.
- Sourced and managed vendors.
- Served as sales coach and accountability partner for new hires.
- Left in September 2021 to complete full stack web development program.

SENIOR ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE

Freightquote / C.H. Robinson | Kansas City, MO May 2014 - April 2021

- Seized single-source opportunities by leveraging proprietary Enterprise SaaS solutions.
- Responsible for sourcing and developing multiple division top-ten accounts.
- Demonstrated ability to negotiate resources and priorities with multiple stakeholders to drive business results.
- Conducted quarterly business reviews with all clients in portfolio.
- Managed day-to-day customer commitments and maintained service levels through use of metrics and analytics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, JavaScript, Python Node.js, Express.js RESTful APIs SQL, Sequelize CompTIA A+ MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, Mongoose

Webpack, React JS, GraphQL Jest, Insomnia, Inquirer ORM, MVC, PWA, MERN Amazon AWS S3 / DynamoDB

SOFT SKILLS

Organized and diligent Project management Risk management Presentation delivery Contract negotiation

Solution / Enterprise-level sales

Vendor management

Analytics

TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGEMENT EXPERIENCE

CODE COMMAND | November 2021 FRONT END DEVELOPER / ASSISTANT PROJECT MANAGER GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/code-command Deployment: code-command-team.herokuapp.com

- Collaborated on a team of two front end developers, and two back end developers.
- Developed project theme, title, and content.
- Selected, sized, and inserted images.
- Conducted daily standup meetings with all team members. Reconciled progress with timeline goals, user story and mockup, then communicated results to Project Manager prior to standup.
- Responsible for development of component and container files. Assisted team members when needed.

FORGE | September 2021 PROJECT MANAGER / FRONT END DEVELOPER / FLOATER GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/Forge Deployment: forge-team.herokuapp.com

- Managed a team consisting of two front end, and two back end developers.
- Prepared and analyzed all requirements and necessary documentation.
- Created mockup using Figma.
- Designed workflow model and established timelines.
- Conducted daily standup meetings with all team members. Reconciled progress with timeline goals, user story and mockup prior to standup. Adjusted workflow and communicated strategy and expectations to the team.

EDUCATION

November 2021

CERTIFICATE - FULL STACK WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

The University of Kansas, Edwards Campus, Overland Park, Kansas

Expected July 2022
BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

California Coast University, Santa Ana, California